#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ nidhiaggarwal1 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Forecasting
Relationship Building
Quarterly Reporting

# Nidhi Aggarwal

Head of Strategy at Vodafone Group, London

London, England, United Kingdom

# Summary

Over 19 years of experience as a strategy, finance and operations expert across sectors and geographies (UK, India, USA, Germany, Singapore, Malaysia and Kuwait). Key areas of expertise:

- Board member and Audit Review Committee for Vodafone Ghana
- Strategy (Portfolio Strategy, Asset Strategy, New Growth Strategy, Partnerships, Business Optimisation, Spectrum auctions, financial valuations, due diligence for market entry)
- Large scale cost transformation programs (£200 mn savings), Capex efficiency, Culture change
- Finance controller for 11 opcos (€8bn revenue), Capex and opex controller for India (£2.0 bn)
- · New business launch and business transformation initiatives
- Managing senior stakeholders (including VF Group Exco members) and large teams

I am an MBA from Indian School of Business and a B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering from IIT, Delhi. During my term at business school, I also went on an exchange program to London Business School. Have done "Digital Transformation – Platform Strategies for Success" from MIT Sloan.

Consistently rated as the top performer/top talent for 12 years at Vodafone, trained through global Inspire talent program and Finance Excellence Program.

# Experience

Vodafone

13 years 3 months

Head of Corporate Development & Strategic Initiatives February 2023 - Present (6 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

Drive planning and integration of proposed merger of VF UK and Three UK

Head of Strategy at Vodafone Group August 2020 - February 2023 (2 years 7 months)

#### Finance Executive

September 2018 - August 2020 (2 years)

London, United Kingdom

Finance Executive, Rest of World (SA, Internationals, Egypt, Ghana, Aus, Ken) (Sep'18-Current)

- Regional leadership role driving strategic business decisions (M&A, Valuations, Spectrum auctions, Capex reviews, Strategic planning, Asset monetisation, Balance Sheet restructuring)
- Running quarterly, half yearly and yearly IR processes and financial certification process
- Leading a team of four high-potential country managers and providing decision support to the regional CEO/CFO/RLT. Managing stakeholders across levels including Group CFO, Group Finance controller, Group M&A and within Opcos ranging from CFO to FP&A team
- Budgeting, Planning and reporting Target setting, budget review, negotiation with Opcos, Exco Ops Review
- Region Governance including Board papers, Audit committee, Audit Risk Paper for board

## VP- Financial Planning & Analysis September 2014 - September 2018 (4 years 1 month)

Mumbai Area, India

Responsible for making investment decisions of > Rs 7,000-10,000 CR capex and managing c. Rs12,000 CR opex

### Head, Corporate Strategy

May 2010 - September 2014 (4 years 5 months)

Long term asset investment Strategy (Spectrum, Spring, M&A)

- Led the development of VIL spectrum strategy and three large scale spectrum acquisition programs (£2.7 bn)
- Proposed the £700m investment plan for a major transformation project (post Verizon deal).
- Developed the M&A strategy for VIL India, conduct first level commercial due diligence for M&A proposals
- Developed strategy of VIL's position on Indus- Vodafone's JV company

**Business Strategy** 

- Developed VIL long term overall strategy partnering with business operations and functions, developed cluster strategy to define strategic objectives for the 23 circles, which are at different evolution levels and at market position
- •Conducted strategy boards with Indian Exco. Significantly contributed in developing VIL strategy and keeping the management focused to identified priorities
- •Competitive and financial performance of large competitors
- Advised the Indian regulatory team on VIL strategic priorities and supported them with arguments to achieve VIL objectives

## Sistema Shyam Teleservices Ltd Project Manager July 2009 - May 2010 (11 months)

- Managed green field launch of voice and high speed data services -Successfully launched six key circles (Delhi, Mumbai, Karnataka, AP, Haryana and Maharashtra)
- Conducted regular launch meeting with the management committee to provide progress on all commercial areas (Marketing, Sales, Customer Service, Finance and SCM)
- Coordinated and liaised with all key stakeholders including CXOs, Circle Head, Circle functional heads and ~40+ people across functions and circles for launch activities for commercial areas

## Diamond Management and Technology Consultants Senior Associate May 2006 - June 2009 (3 years 2 months)

- Served six clients in telecom, new media and financial services across India,
   Middle East and US
- Extensive consulting experience in Business Strategy, Program Management and Performance Improvement issues
- Advised clients on core strategy issues like growth strategy, business planning, go/no-go decision for market entry and market assessment.
   Highlights include
- Financial valuation of 3G and BWA license as part of auction strategy for a fast growing telecom player in India
- Long term business planning of 2G business of a leading telecom player in India
- Market assessment and business feasibility for a financial information portal in India

- Customer positioning and marketing strategy for a newly launched business news website
- Market sizing of printing opportunities in India
- Consulted clients on program management and process improvement issues.
   Highlights include
- Large scale program management of INR 400 M internet portal launch
- Process Improvement in vendor management and IT service delivery management

#### i2 Technologies

Sr. Consultant

June 2002 - April 2005 (2 years 11 months)

- Executed large-scale supply chain projects in four different industry verticals
   viz. Semiconductor, Consumer Electronics, Metals and Apparels
- Worked in five countries viz Singapore, Malaysia, Germany, USA and India
- Exceeded client expectations which resulted in securing additional \$2M project from a leading semi-conductor client in Malaysia
- Handled multiple accounts simultaneously, led cross-functional teams and managed daily operations between onsite and offshore teams
- Captured business requirements, designed and developed large scale data models, implemented solution to resolve supply chain issues of material and capacity planning

# Education

**London Business School** 

MBA, Finance · (2006 - 2007)

Indian School of Business

MBA, Finance, Marketing · (2005 - 2006)

Indian School of Business

MBA, Strategy, Finance and Marketing (2005 - 2006)

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

B Tech, Mechanical Engineering · (1998 - 2002)